# Wojciech Urbański

Senior front-end developer, Trainer

# Summary

Experienced front-end web developer with agile mindset strongly focused on the customer. Specialties: agile / scrum, object oriented JavaScript, HTML, CSS, UX, accessibility, design. Interested in modern frameworks (e.g. Vue.js, React.js, Angular.js) and tools (Webpack, Gulp, Browserify). Good UX and user centered design enthusiast.

# Experience

# Senior developer (front-end) at SentiOne

#### February 2017 - Present

SentiOne tracks global and local brands and measures consumer opinions and activities in social media and online platforms. With our smart tools our customers gain stronger insights and analytics that will help them make better decisions.

As a front-end developer, I am working closely with PM, UX and other developers on a Scala/React.js application to deliver the best user experience possible - having as much impact as possible. Within a year we managed to redesign the whole app while making it much more maintainable.

Front-end stack includes React.js, Reflux.js, SCSS, Webpack, Jest.

# Trainer / Coach at infoShare Academy

June 2017 - Present

I run a dedicated Vue.js + vue-router + Vuex trainings. Vue.js was love at first sight for me and I want to share some of that passion with others. Contact me if you want one for your team.

# Consultant, Trainer, Web developer

### April 2011 - Present

Everything for the web with strong focus on front-end development. I also run dedicated Vue.js trainings and consulting.

# Senior developer (front-end) at Spartez / Atlassian

July 2015 - January 2017 (1 year 7 months)

Working as front-end / full stack developer on the JIRA team. Most recently working on Spartez' own products and services. Developing projects in OO JavaScript - Backbone Marionette, web components and Vue.js.

Actively helping other developers with front-end tasks and raising awareness about good frontend practices, mentoring new hires. Taking part in the recruitment process (conducted over 150 interviews). Working in an international environment.

## Front-end developer at Spartez / Atlassian

October 2012 - June 2015 (2 years 9 months)

Working as a front-end developer on the JIRA team. Developing projects in OO JavaScript, mostly Backbone Marionette. Actively helping other developers with front-end tasks and raising awareness about good front-end practices. Taking part in the recruitment process. Working in an international environment. I was also responsible for running and organizing brown-bag sessions within the company for over a year - we started to have a regular weekly talks on various subjects.

I am one of the two developers who shaped and created what later became JIRA Service Desk.

I was part of the team that designed and created smart in-context issue creation feature on agile boards in JIRA. Successfully designed, coded and delivered to customers the wiki markup editor in JIRA as ShipIt (internal hackathon) and then 20%-time project.

## Senior front-end developer at Tribal Internet Solutions

April 2012 - September 2012 (6 months)

Establishing comapny's front-end standards. Implementing layouts basing on the designs, developing jQuery plug-ins, R&D on code quality improvement. Recruiting and training new front-end developers. Contacting and managing external developers. Maintaining existing websites. Company's wiki implementation. Working in international environment - daily communication and creating technical documentation in English.

#### Front-end web developer at Tribal Internet Solutions

April 2011 - March 2012 (1 year)

Implementing layouts basing on the designs, developing jQuery plug-ins, developing websites in Umbraco CMS/CMF with heavy use of XSLT. Maintaining existing websites. Working in international environment - daily communication and creating technical documentation in English.

#### Web Developer / designer

December 2005 - April 2011 (5 years 5 months)

Designing websites, logos and business cards; Implementing front-end and back-end; using simple SEO techniques; getting new and managing existing clients.

#### Participant

July 2010 - December 2010 (6 months)

External links based advertising network startup – Adternative.net.

Naming, logo and website design, front-end development (HTML5, CSS3, jQuery), online marketing, talking to potential investors.

Trainee at Gratka Technologie Sp. z o.o.

August 2009 - October 2009 (3 months)

Prototyping (Axure), designing (Photoshop) and implementing user interface of an in-house HR application. PHP programming.

# Education

Technical University of Gdansk Master of Science (MSc), Computer Science, 2007 - 2012

# Wojciech Urbański

Senior front-end developer, Trainer



Contact Wojciech on LinkedIn